<chapter>
 <title>Love</title>
 <author>Egil Möller</author>
 <copyright>1997-1998, 2001, 2003, 2005</copyright>
 <translation>
  <author>Egil Möller and Paul Westwood</author>
  <copyright>2006</copyright>
 </translation>
 <language>english</language>
 <header>
  <chapter>Lonlieness is our greatest enemy, even if not many admits
  it. And even with our dearest friends around us, yes even when we
  are with the one we love, are we alone...</chapter>
 </header>

 <chapter>
  <title>2003</title>
  <chapter id="faageln">
   <title>The bird</title>

   <chapter>Once uppon a time there was a bird living in a cage in the
   home of a small boy. He'd got the bird as a birthday present from
   his father, and he was so happy. Everyday the boy fed, watered and
   talked to the bird. He brought it out with him on his excursions to
   the forrest, and he showed it all his precious hideouts there. But
   the bird was silent, it never answered him when he talked to it,
   and even though it seemed to like being carried out in the forest,
   and it looked interrested at all of his hideouts, it wasnt
   happy.</chapter>

   <chapter>One evening when the boy came home from the forest with
   his bird, just as the sun was about to set, he asked it why it
   wasn't happy. He wished so much for it to be happy, just like him.
   As usual, the bird didn't reply, because as you well know, birds
   can't do that. But it looked up at the open window, where you could
   see some birds passing by, with envy and sorrow in its eyes. The
   boy looked at the birds for a long time, and then, without uttering
   a word, he carried the cage to the window and opened its
   gate.</chapter>
   
   <chapter>The boy stood there, in the open window, for a long, long
   time, watching the bird slowly disappearing in the
   distance.</chapter>

   <chapter>He took the cage and carried it out in the woods, and he
   talked to the bird that didn't reply, since it wasn't there. Every
   day thereafter the boy did as usual, he showed the forest and all
   his precious hideouts to the bird that had flown away.</chapter>

   <image><width>2.8</width><location>pictures</location><name>Faageln</name></image>

  </chapter>

  <chapter id="farbrodern">
   <title>The old man</title>

   <chapter>The sun casts long rays along the ground, between the
   trees that stand sparesly in the park, over the young who sit in
   the grass, or walk arm in arm. In the middle of all this life, in
   the middle of the spring, there's an old man sitting on a wooden
   bench, his face turned towards the sun. He's placed his hat at his
   side, and his overcoat hangs over the bench. He shades his eyes
   with one hand and looks past the sun, out in the clear eavening
   sky.</chapter>

   <chapter>A young couple passes by, hand in hand. Two boys. For a
   moment they obscure his sky. He raises his fist towards them, as if
   trying to swipe them away. Not because they're boys, not because
   they're in love, or perhaps a little bit for that, but because they
   are young, because they are in his way, because they are cute,
   lovely and loving. He doesn't like the loving, the old
   man.</chapter>

   <chapter>They're at their worst in the spring, when they sworm the
   place like slugs after rain. Slimeing their way through the park,
   leaving a trace of pink (slisk). No, he much preferes those of his
   own age. Their bodies and thoughts have long since forgotten how it
   once felt to be like that. Now they are shrunken and dried like
   raisins. Now they resemble him fully. That is probably the main
   reason he dislikes youth, that he never got to be like them, that
   he was like he is now, all along.</chapter>

   <chapter>They are past him now, his view once more undisturbed, and
   he forgives them, oh he forgives them, for they give him life for a
   second while he watches them. At least he gets to sit there on the
   bench and watch life, even if he can't live it. They don't know
   what they have given him - a piece of their love. He can live on
   that for days.</chapter>

   <chapter>And a tear finds its way down from his blue eye.</chapter>

  </chapter>
 </chapter>

 <chapter>
  <title>1997-2001</title>
  <chapter>
   <title>Endia</title>

   <chapter>If you take bus 324 to its final destination, and the
   bicycles for 9 k along a dirt road shaded from all sun by beeches,
   the few days the sun actually shines, you get to a small unpainted
   gray wooden cottage with a corrogated steel roof. The only thing
   revealing that the house isn't abandoned several years ago is a
   parabol antenna on a pole in the overgrown gardern.</chapter>

   <chapter>It's late, it's pitch black and it's raining so heavily
   that even the hardy weeds in the garden has been thrown to the
   ground. The only light around is the blue flickering light of a
   computer-screen in one of the windows. There is a boy, but he
   preferes to think of himself as a yung man, in front of the screen.
   His finger caressing the keyboard, barely leaving it, his sight
   lost far off in the world of icons and texts.</chapter>

   <chapter>There is a distant thunder and the boy spells out a few
   commands, misspells them and has to redo it several times. He is
   stressed, sweat surfacing on his forehead. Finally, the screen is
   empty except for the message "Computer correctly taken down for
   system maintance. Please turn off main power." in red. The boy
   quickly disconects all cables, grabs a (filt) from the bed, wraps
   himself in it and lays down, or rather falles down, into the bed.
   He's tired, he hasn't slept for the last 35 hours...</chapter>

   <chapter>He dreams, about Endia, the girl in the class above his.
   She's like everybody else, talking about unimportant thing, but
   still not really. She has changed, or is it he who has changed? Is
   he slowly becoming one of them? Oh, he hates them, all those users,
   who think they know everything, but who know nothing and asks about
   everything fifteen times after you've explained it to them. He can
   still feel the hate that welled up inside him when the teacher
   warned him about the trace program. ....</chapter>

  </chapter>

  <chapter>
   <title>Lina</title>

   <chapter>This story has not yet been translated. Please come back
   later or check-out the swedish version.</chapter>

  </chapter>
 </chapter>

 <chapter>
  <class>about</class>
  <chapter>This text is free software; you can redistribute it
  and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License
  as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of
  the License, or (at your option) any later version.</chapter>

  <chapter>This text is distributed in the hope that it will be
  useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty
  of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
  General Public License for more details.</chapter>

  <chapter>You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public
  License along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
  Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307
  USA</chapter>
 </chapter>
</chapter>
